Christopher Leja

Brooklyn, NY, 11221 | 970-219-4766 | christopher.leja@gmail.com GitHub | Medium | https://christopher-leja-portfolio.vercel.app/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks. My writing background has given me extensive experience with learning syntax, creative problem solving, and linguistic pattern recognition, skills that translate directly to writing code. I've edited a best-selling poetry collection and am a multiple Pushcart Prize nominee. Coding offers exciting new opportunities to connect people through dynamic, interactive stories, and I am excited to help tell them.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.is, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Material, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Maiestro - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo | Live Demo

A music app designed to jumpstart creativity—allows users to play songs, save, record, and duet with a neural network.

- Utilized a session-based Rails API structure for authentication and authorization.
- Used Magenta is and machine learning to continue user-generated melodies in duet mode.
- Built custom recording feature using React.
- Implemented a dynamic, responsive keyboard, allowing users to change instruments, octaves, and range.
- Used a Rails backend, allowing users to save and load songs they've recorded.

Drumblr - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

A virtual drum machine designed as an homage to late 80's/early 90's step-sequencers.

- Implemented user interface using React to allow users to create dynamic beats.
- Utilized midi-sounds-react library to retrieve samples, allowing users to create, play and edit beats in real time.
- Used React and the midi-sounds react library to ensure creating beats was connectivity independent.
- Used Rails to build backend functionality, allowing users to save and load beats.

Super Pet Bros. Unleashed - GitHub | Video Demo

A Pokémon-style browser game allowing users to create, save, and battle with their selected champions.

- Used vanilla JavaScript to implement frontend logic and combat mechanics (damage, attack effects, turn structure).
- Utilized Rails as a backend API to save new champions with their selected move sets.
- Used JavaScript to render dynamically updating pages based on user input and battle information.
- Built frontend logic and battle page rendering using JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

Clean Fuels Development Coalition

Communications Consultant

Bethesda, MD 02/2019 - 02/2020

- Collaboratively developed long-term media strategies and handled media outreach for a national ad campaign.
- Oversaw social media campaigns that generated over 50,000 new engagements.
- Collaborated on campaigns resulting in core messages appearing in <u>Forbes</u>, <u>The Hill</u> and the <u>Des Moines Register</u>.

Sans Serif Writer, IMPACT 2019 Conference

San Francisco, CA 04/2019 - 10/2019

- Wrote and reviewed materials for <u>Charles Schwab's IMPACT 2019 Conference</u> to ensure quality and clarity.
- Created guide materials clarifying workshops and speaker biographies for thousands of conference attendees.

Teaching Artist/Freelance editor

Self-Employed

02/2012 - 02/2020

Traveling

Orchestrated and executed multiple national and international tours as a teaching artist.

- Designed, organized and conducted hundreds of readings and workshops.
- Served as primary creative editor for Clementine von Radics' <u>Mouthful of Forevers</u>, which sold over 60,000 copies, and was nominated for a Goodreads Choice Award (Best Poetry Collection).
- Facilitated writing workshops in universities, high schools, and juvenile detention facilities.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stock Web Development, Buby on Boile and Jove Script program

Brooklyn, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

02/2020 - 06/2020

Lewis & Clark College

Portland, OR 05/2012

Bachelor of Arts, English Major, Communications Minor